米 高 梅
出品
绿野仙踪
翻译 校对  时间轴 特效制作： 醉梦
朱迪·嘉兰 饰 多萝西
弗兰克·摩根 饰 魔法师和马维尔教授
雷·博尔格 饰 稻草人和汉克
伯特·拉尔 饰 狮子和杰克
杰克·海利 饰 锡人和希格利
碧莉·伯克 饰 北方女巫葛琳达
玛格丽特·汉密尔顿 饰 西方女巫和高驰小姐
查利·格拉普文 饰 亨利叔叔
克拉拉·布兰迪克 饰 艾姆婶婶
制片
马文·李洛
导演
维多·佛莱明
将近四十年来，本故事感动
无数内心保持年轻的朋友
故事的真谛经久不衰
献给对此深信不疑的你们
及心中永远保持年轻的人
她还没来吧 托托
She isn't coming yet, Toto.
她弄痛你了吗
Did she hurt you?
她一直很想的 对不对
She tried to, didn't she?
走吧 我们去跟亨利叔叔和艾姆婶婶说
Come on. We'll go tell Uncle Henry and Auntie Em.
走吧 托托
Come on, Toto.
艾姆婶婶 艾姆婶婶
Aunt Em! Aunt Em.
听我说高驰小姐如何对托托...
Listen to what Miss Gulch did to Toto--
多萝西 抱歉 我们在数东西
Dorothy, please. We're counting.
-但是她打它... -现在别打扰我们 甜心
- But she hit him-- - Don't bother us now, honey.
孵蛋器坏了 我们会损失许多小鸡
The incubator's gone bad and we're likely to lose a lot of our chicks.
可怜的小东西
Oh, that poor little thing.
但是高驰小姐用耙子打托托...
But Miss Gulch hit Toto with a rake...
因为她说托托天天跑进花园 追她的脏猫...
...because she says he chases her nasty old cat every day.
...七十只 多萝西 拜托
--seventy. Dorothy, please.
但它又不是每天都跑去 一周只有一两次
But he doesn't do it every day. Just once or twice a week.
但它根本抓不到她的猫
He can't catch her old cat anyway.
-现在她又说要去找警长来 -多萝西 我们很忙
- And now she says she's gonna-- - Dorothy. Dorothy, we're busy.
好吧
Oh, all right.
-怎么样 -别急
- How's she coming? - .Take it easy.
哦
Ow!
你压到我的手指头了
You got my finger.
你为什么不把你的手拿开
Get your finger out of the way.
好了
There you are.
就压在我手指头上
Right on my finger.
幸好没压到你的头
Lucky it wasn't your head.
杰可 我要怎么处理高驰小姐 就因为托托
Zeke, what am I gonna do about Miss Gulch? Just because Toto--
听着 甜心 我要去把猪只赶进去
Listen, honey, I got them hogs to get in.
多萝西 你没有动脑子 我看你根本没有脑袋
Dorothy, you ain't using your head. You'd think you didn't have any brains.
-我当然有脑袋 -那你为何不用呢
- I have so got brains. - Well, why don't you use them?
别经过高驰小姐的家
Don't go by Miss Gulch's place.
那托托就进不了她的园子 你也不会有麻烦了 明白吗
Then Toto won't get in her garden, and you won't get in no trouble, see?
汉克 你就是不听我说 算了吧
Oh, Hunk, you just won't listen, that's all.
你知道 你的头不是稻草做的
Well, your head ain't made of straw, you know.
在我从你们身上赚到钱之前 先进去
Say, get in there before I make a dime bank out of you.
听着 孩子...
Listen, kid...
你想让高驰那头老母牛来咬你吗
...are you gonna let that old Gulch heifer try and buffalo you?
她没有什么好怕的 有点勇气
She ain't nothing to be afraid of. Have a little courage.
我才不怕她
I'm not afraid of her.
下次她再喊叫 就走到她面前朝她吐口水
Next time she squawks, walk up to her and spit in her eye.
-我就会这么做 -哦 哦
- That's what I'd do. - Oh! Oh!
杰可
Oh! Zeke!
杰可 救命啊 帮帮我 把我弄出去
Help! Help me, Zeke! Get me out of here!
救命
Help!
哦
Oh! Oh!
-你没事吧 多萝西 -是的 我没事
- Are you all right, Dorothy? - Yes, I'm all right.
我掉下去了 然后杰可...
I fell in, and Zeke--
怎么啦 杰可 你和我一样害怕
Why, Zeke, you're just as scared as I am.
你会让一只小猪给吓破胆吗
You gonna let a little old pig make a coward out of you?
看你...
Look at you--
在胡闹些什么 还有很多活要干呢
What's all this jabber-wapping when there's work to be done?
我知道有三个农场工人要失业了
I know three farm hands that'll be out of a job.
多萝西是...
Dorothy was--
我看到你在修补那个装置
I saw you tinkering with that contraption.
-你和汉克回到马车上 -好吧
- You and Hunk get back to that wagon. - All right.
但总有一天他们会给我立一座雕像...
But someday they'll erect a statue to me--
好了 现在别摆姿势了
Well, don't start posing for it now.
不能空腹干活 吃些煎饼吧
Can't work on an empty stomach. Have some crullers.
-谢谢 盖尔夫人 -刚炸的
Gosh, Mrs. Gale. - Just fried.
你看 多萝西掉进了猪圈...
You see, Dorothy toppled into the--
多萝西就不应该待在猪圈周围
It's no place for Dorothy around a pigsty.
快去喂猪 不然它们会发脾气
Feed those hogs before they worry themselves into anemia.
-好 -艾姆婶婶...
- Yes. - Auntie Em...
你知道高驰小姐说 要怎么对待托托吗
...you know what Miss Gulch said she was going to do to Toto?
-她说她会... -别再胡思乱想了
- She said she'd-- - Stop imagining things.
你总是为小事烦恼 你今天就帮大家
You always get in a fret over nothing. You just help us out today...
去找个不会惹麻烦的地方吧
...and find yourself a place where you won't get into any trouble.
一个没有任何麻烦的地方
Someplace where there isn't any trouble.
你认为有这样的地方吗 托托
Do you suppose there is such a place, Toto?
一定有吧
There must be.
那不是一个你乘船或火车 就能到达的地方
It's not a place you can get to by a boat or a train.
很远很远的地方
It's far, far away.
在月亮之后...
Behind the moon...
雨水之外
...beyond the rain...
越过彩虹 又译：彩虹之上(演唱:朱迪·嘉兰) -- Over The Rainbow (Judy Garland)
越过彩虹之处
Somewhere over the rainbow
高高蓝天之上
Way up high
我在小夜曲中听过的地方
There's a land that I heard of
有个遥远的国度
Once in a lullaby
越过彩虹之处
Somewhere over the rainbow
天空如此蔚蓝
Skies are blue
你所编织的梦想
And the dreams that you dare to dream
都能在此一一实现
Really do come true
有天我对星星许愿
Someday I'll wish upon a star
醒来只见云彩远远在我后面
And wake up where the clouds Are far behind me
所有烦恼都融化
Where troubles melt like lemon drops
从烟囱飘走
Away above the chimney tops
那便是你能找着我的地方
That's where you'll Find me
越过彩虹之处
Somewhere over the rainbow
有蓝鸟飞舞
Bluebirds fly
鸟儿越过彩虹之处飞舞
Birds fly over the rainbow
那么为什么
Why then
为什么我不能
Oh why can't I
如果快乐的蓝鸟
If happy little bluebirds fly
能越过彩虹飞舞
Beyond the rainbow
为什么 为什么
Why oh why
我不能
Can't I
-盖尔先生 -你好 高驰小姐
- Mr. Gale. - Howdy, Miss Gulch.
我要马上与你和你太太谈谈多萝西的事
I want to see you and your wife about Dorothy.
-多萝西做了什么 -她做了什么
- What has Dorothy done? - What's she done?
我的腿被咬了 几乎瘸了
I'm all but lame from the bite on my leg.
-你是说她咬了你 -不 是她的狗
- You mean, she bit you? - No, her dog.
她咬了她的狗 嗯
Oh, she bit her dog, eh?
不是
No.
那条狗很危险 我要送到警长那里去杀死
That dog's a menace. I'm taking him to make sure he's destroyed.
杀死 托托
Destroyed. Toto?
你不能这样做 你不可以
Oh, you can't. You mustn't.
艾姆婶婶 亨利叔叔 你们不会让她这么做吧
Auntie Em. Uncle Henry. You won't let her, will you?
我们当然不会
Of course we won't.
对不对 艾姆
will we, Em?
求求你 艾姆婶婶
Please, Aunt Em.
托托不知道它做错了什么
Toto didn't know he was doing anything wrong.
应该惩罚我才是 让我不吃晚饭就上床睡觉
I'm the one that ought to be punished. Send me to bed without supper.
把狗交给我 否则我去告你 把你的农场扣押
Hand over that dog or I'll bring a suit that'll take your farm.
法律保护人们不被狗咬伤
The law protects folks against dogs that bite.
如果她把它拴起来呢 它很和善
How about if she keeps him tied up? He's gentle.
-对和善的人一直很和善 -那得由警长决定
- With gentle people, that is. - That's for the sheriff to decide.
这是允许我带走狗的命令 除非你想违反法律
This order allows me to take him. Unless you wanna go against the law.
对
Hm. Yes.
我们不能违反法律 恐怕可怜的托托得走了
We can't go against the law. I'm afraid poor Toto has to go.
-现在你明白了 -不行
- Now you're seeing reason. - No.
我用这个装它 这样它就不能再攻击我了
Here's what I'm taking him in, so he can't attack me again.
不 不行 我不会让你带走它
No,no. I won't let you take him.
-你走开 不然我要亲自咬你 -多萝西
- You go away or I'll bite you myself! - Dorothy.
你这个邪恶的老巫婆
You wicked old witch.
亨利叔叔 艾姆婶婶 别让她带走托托
Uncle Henry, Auntie Em, don't let her take Toto.
我有命令
I've got an order.
-把它给我 -请住手
- Let me have him. - Please stop.
把它放进篮子里 亨利
Put him in the basket, Henry.
-这才对 -别这样 亨利叔叔
- The idea. - Don't, Uncle Henry.
托托
Oh, Toto.
阿尔米拉·高驰 别以为你有警长的命令...
Almira Gulch, just because you own half the county...
就有权利来管理我们
...doesn't mean you can run the rest of us.
二十三年来 我一直想告诉你我对你的看法
For 23 years I've been dying to tell you what I thought of you.
而现在
And now--
作为一个基督徒得我 还是说不出口
Well, being a Christian woman, I can't say it.
托托 亲爱的
Toto, darling.
我又看到你了 你跑回来了
Oh, I got you back. You came back.
我太高兴了 托托
I'm so glad.toto.
他们很快会回来找你
They'll be coming back for you in a minute.
我们必须逃走
We've got to get away.
We've got to run away.
马维尔教授
欧洲皇室的赏识
水晶球告诉你 过去 现在和未来
好啊 有客人来了
Well, well, well. Houseguests, eh?
你可能是谁
And who might you be?
不 不要告诉我
No, no. Now, don't tell me.
让我来猜猜 你是...
Let's see. You're--
你在乔装旅行
You're traveling in disguise.
不对 那不对 你是...
No, that's not right. You're--
你要去拜访人
You're going on a visit.
不 我错了 让我们看看...
No, I'm wrong. Let's see what we--
你...你离家出走
You're-- You're running away.
你怎么猜出来的
How did you guess?
马维尔教授从不猜测 他就是知道
Professor Marvel never guesses, he knows.
你为什么要离家出走 不 别告诉我
Now, why are you running away? No, no. Now, don't tell me.
因为家人不理解你 他们不欣赏你
They-- They don't understand you at home. They don't appreciate you.
你想看看别的地方 繁华都市 高山大海
You want to see other lands. Big cities, big mountains, big oceans.
为什么 好像你能读懂我的内心一样
Why, it's just like you could read what was inside of me.
托托 这样很不礼貌 人家还没请我们吃呢
Toto, that's not polite. We haven't been asked yet.
它太受欢迎了
Oh, he's perfectly welcome.
狗都是这样 嗯
As one dog to another, huh?
刚才我们说到哪了
Now, let's see, where were we?
我们能不能跟你一起去看欧洲的皇室
Why can't we go with you and see all the crowned heads of Europe?
你知道这些 噢 你是说招牌上的那件事
Do you know any? Oh, you mean the thing. Yes.
呃 我做什么事都要先问问我的水晶
Well, uh, I never do anything without consulting my crystal first.
我们去里面 跟我来 我来给你看
Let's go inside here. We'll-- Just come along. I'll show you.
没错 就在这里
That's right. Here.
坐在这里 那就是它
Sit right down here. That's it.
这是同样的真品 魔法 真正的水晶
This is the same genuine, magic, authentic crystal...
埃及法老时代 伊西斯和奥西里斯的祭司使用
...used by the priests of Isis and Osiris in the days of the Pharaohs...
克莉奥帕特拉看到了凯撒和安东尼的到来
...in which Cleopatra saw the approach of Julius Caesar and Marc Anthony.
克莉奥帕特拉：又称埃及艳后 古埃及最后一个女王
及诸如此类事情
And so on, and so on.
现在...
Now...
孩子 你最好闭上眼睛 一会儿...
...you'd better close your eyes, my child, for a moment...
以便更好地与无限的事物和谐相处
...in order to be better in tuned with the Infinite.
我们做这些事情离不开无限的触角
We can't do these things without reaching out into the Infinite.
好 可以了 现在你可以睁开眼了
Yes, that's all right. Now you can open them.
我来注视着水晶
We'll gaze into the crystal.
啊
Ah.
我看到的是什么 一间有篱笆围墙的房子
What's this I see? A house with a picket fence...
还有一个带风向标的谷仓
...and a barn with a weathervane...
一匹奔跑的马
...of a running horse.
-那是我们的农场 -对
- That's our farm. - Yes.
对 有位妇女
Yes. There's a woman.
她穿着件有圆点的裙子 她面容憔悴
She's wearing a polka-dot dress. Her face is careworn.
那是艾姆婶婶
That's Aunt Em.
对 她的名字叫艾米丽
Yes. Her name is Emily.
没错 她在干什么
That's right. What's she doing?
我看不太清楚
Well, I can't quite see.
她在哭泣 有人伤了她的心
Why, she's crying. Someone has hurt her.
有人几乎让她心碎
Someone has just about broken her heart.
是我吗
Me?
是她深爱着的人
Well, it's-- It's someone she loves very much.
一个慈祥友善对待的人
Someone she's been very kind to.
在她生病时照顾过的人
Someone she's taken care of in sickness.
我得过一次麻疹 她每分钟都陪着我
I had the measles once, and she stayed right by me every minute.
嗯哼
Uh-huh.
她现在在干什么
What's she doing now?
她...这是什么
Yes, she's-- What's this?
她把手放在心口上
Why, she's putting her hand on her heart.
-她跌坐在床上 -不好了
- She's dropping down on the bed. - Oh, no, no.
就这些 水晶球变暗了
Well, that's all. The crystal's gone dark.
你认为她不会真的生病了吧
You don't suppose she could really be sick, do you?
-我必须马上回家 -我以为你要和我一起去
- Oh, I've gotta go home right away. - I thought you were going with me.
不行 我得马上回到她身边
No, I have to get to her right away.
快 托托 快
Come on, Toto. Come on.
再见 马维尔教授 非常感谢
Goodbye, Professor Marvel. And thanks a lot.
最好躲起来 西尔维斯特 暴风雨要来了
Better get under cover, Sylvester. A storm's blowing up.
用农民的土话来说 这纯粹是弥天大谎
A whopper, to speak in the vernacular of the peasantry.
可怜的孩子 希望她能平安到家
Poor little kid. I hope she gets home all right.
快把马放了
Get them horses loose!
希格利呢 希格利
Where's Hickory? Hickory?
该死
Doggone it.
是龙卷风 是龙卷风
It's a twister! It's a twister!
多萝西
Dorothy!
大家都到避风地下室去
Everybody in the storm cellar!
亨利 我找不到多萝西 她在外面的暴风中
Henry, I can't find Dorothy! She's out in the storm.
我们现在不能去找她
We can't look for her now.
快到地下室去 赶快
Come on, get in the cellar. Hurry up.
艾姆婶婶
Auntie Em!
Auntie Em?
艾姆婶婶
Auntie Em!
艾姆婶婶 亨利叔叔
Auntie Em! Uncle Henry!
艾姆婶婶
Auntie Em!
我们一定是在龙卷风里面
We must be up inside the cyclone!
高驰小姐
Oh! Miss Gulch.
哦
Oh!
托托...
Toto...
我觉得我们已经不在堪萨斯了
...I have a feeling we're not in Kansas anymore.
我们一定越过了彩虹之处
We must be over the rainbow.
现在我知道我们不在堪萨斯
Now I know we're not in Kansas.
你是好女巫还是坏女巫
Are you a good witch or a bad witch?
谁 我吗
Who, me?
哎呀 我根本不是女巫
Why, I'm not a witch at all.
-我叫多萝西·盖尔 来自堪萨斯 -噢
- I'm Dorothy Gale, from Kansas. - Oh.
那它是巫师吗
Well, is that the witch?
谁 托托 托托是我的狗
Who, Toto? Toto's my dog.
我有点糊涂了 芒奇金人呼唤我是因为有个新女巫...
I'm a little muddled. The Munchkins called me because a new witch...
刚刚把房子压在东方的坏女巫身上
...just dropped a house on the Wicked Witch of the East.
房子在那里 你在这里...
And there's the house, and here you are...
那就是东方坏女巫剩下的部分
...and that's all that's left of the Wicked Witch of the East.
芒奇金人想知道 你是好女巫还是坏女巫
What the Munchkins want to know is, are you a good witch or a bad witch?
但我已经告诉过你了 我根本不是女巫
But I've already told you, I'm not a witch at all.
女巫都是又老又丑
Witches are old and ugly.
那是什么
What was that?
芒奇金人 他们笑是因为我也是女巫
The Munchkins. They're laughing because I am a witch.
我是葛琳达 北方女巫
I'm Glinda, the Witch of the North.
你是女巫
You are?
对不起
Oh, I beg your pardon.
但我以前从没听说过会有美丽的女巫
But I've never heard of a beautiful witch before.
只有坏女巫才会丑恶
Only bad witches are ugly.
芒奇金人很高兴 因为你从邪恶的东方女巫...
The Munchkins are happy because you freed them...
-手中解救了他们 -请问 什么是芒奇金人
- ...from the Wicked Witch of the East. - But if you please, what are Munchkins?
住在这里的小人儿 这里叫芒奇金国
The little people who live here. It's Munchkinland...
你是他们全国的英雄 亲爱的
...and you are their national heroine, my dear.
没关系 你们都可以出来感谢她
It's all right. You may all come out and thank her.
出来 出来 不管你在哪里
Come out, come out Wherever you are
见见那个从星星上掉下来的小女孩
And meet the young lady Who fell from a star
她从天上掉下来 是来自非常遥远的地方
She fell from the sky She fell very far
她说 堪萨斯是那颗星星的名字
And Kansas, she says Is the name of the star
她说 堪萨斯
Kansas, she says
是那颗星星的名字
Is the name of the star
她为你们带来好消息
She brings you good news
你们可曾听说过
Or haven't you heard
当她从堪萨斯掉下来
When she fell out of Kansas
奇迹就发生了
A miracle occurred
这并不是什么奇迹 事情不过这样
It really was no miracle What happened was just this
大风开始刮起 房子跟着飞起
The wind began to switch The house to pitch
突然间 天摇地动的震撼
And suddenly the hinges Started to unhitch
就在这时 女巫 贪心无比
Just then the Witch To satisfy an itch
骑着她的扫帚 却还想搭便车
Went flying on her broomstick Thumbing for a hitch
当时发生的事真是变化多端
And oh, what happened then was rich
房子开始摇动
The house began to pitch
厨房跟着裂了
The kitchen took a slitch
坏女巫就被压在沟槽中央
It landed on the Wicked Witch In the middle of a ditch
对坏女巫而言 真是恶运临头
Which was not a healthy situation For the Wicked Witch
房子开始摇动 厨房跟着裂了
The house began to pitch The kitchen took a slitch
坏女巫就被压在沟槽中央
It landed on the Wicked Witch In the middle of a ditch
对坏女巫而言 真是恶运临头
Which was not a healthy situation For the Wicked Witch
她就开始抽搐 逐渐失去气息
Who began to twitch And was reduced to just a stitch
邪恶的女巫就此死去
Of what was once the Wicked Witch
我们由衷的感谢你
We thank you very sweetly
把事情处理的干净利落
For doing it so neatly
你彻底的杀死了她
You've killed her so completely
我们由衷的感谢你
That we thank you very sweetly
把这欢乐的消息传出去 邪恶的老巫婆终于死了
Let the joyous news be spread. The Wicked Old Witch at last is dead.
叮当 老巫婆已经死了
Ding-Dong! The Witch is dead
哪位老巫婆 那位坏巫婆
Which old witch The Wicked Witch
叮当 老巫婆已经死了
Ding-Dong! The Wicked Witch is dead
快起来 瞌睡虫 揉揉眼 快起床
Wake up you sleepyhead Rub your eyes get out of bed
邪恶巫婆已经死了
Wake up, the Wicked Witch is dead
她去小妖精的地方了 在很深很深的地底
She's gone where the goblins go Below below below
让我们敞开心扉 放声歌唱 敲响钟声
Yo-ho! Let's open up and sing And ring the bells out
叮当之声多快乐 高声唱 低声吟
Ding-Dong! The merry-o Sing it high, sing it low
让大家知道邪恶巫婆已经死了
Let them know The Wicked Witch is dead
作为绿野仙境里的
As mayor of the Munchkin City
芒奇金市的市长
In the county of the Land of Oz
我非常隆重地欢迎你
I welcome you most regally
但我们必须从法律上加以验证
But we've got to verify it legally
-去看看 -去看看
- To see - To see?
-她是否 -她是否
- If she - If she?
在道德上 伦理上
Is morally ethically
-精神上 肉体上 -肯定的 绝对的
- Spiritually physically - Positively absolutely
不可否认和可靠的死亡
Undeniably and reliably dead
作为验尸官我必须确认
As coroner I must aver
死亡证明
我彻底的检验了她
I thoroughly examined her
她不是垂死
And she's not only merely dead
她真的是完全死去了
She's really most sincerely dead
今天 是我们所有的...
Then this is a Day of Independence...
芒奇金人和子孙独立的日子
...for all the Munchkins and their descendants.
没错
If any!
让快乐的消息传播 邪恶的老巫婆终于死了
Yes, let the joyous news be spread. The Wicked Old Witch at last is dead.
叮当 老巫婆死了
Ding-Dong The Witch is dead
哪位老巫婆 那位邪恶巫婆
Which old witch The Wicked Witch
叮当 邪恶的巫婆已经死了
Ding-Dong The Wicked Witch is dead
快起来 瞌睡虫 揉揉眼 快起床
Wake up you sleepyhead Rub your eyes get out of bed
快起来 邪恶的巫婆已经死了
Wake up The Wicked Witch is dead
她去小妖精的地方了 在很深很深的地底
She's gone where the goblins go Below below below
让我们敞开心扉 放声歌唱 敲响钟声
Yo-ho! Let's open up and sing And ring the bells out
叮当之声多快乐 高声唱 低声吟
Ding-Dong! The merry-o Sing it high, sing it low
让大家知道邪恶巫婆已经死了
Let them know the Wicked Witch is dead
我们代表摇篮曲协会
We represent the Lullaby League
摇篮曲协会 摇篮曲协会
The Lullaby League The Lullaby League
以摇篮曲协会的名义
And in the name of the Lullaby League
我们欢迎你来到芒奇金市
We wish to welcome you To Munchkinland
我们代表棒棒糖公会
We represent the Lollipop Guild
棒棒糖公会 棒棒糖公会
The Lollipop Guild The Lollipop Guild
以棒棒糖公会名义
And in the name of the Lollipop Guild
我们欢迎你来到芒奇金市
We wish to welcome you To Munchkinland
我们欢迎你来到芒奇金
We welcome you to Munchkinland
啦啦啦 啦啦啦 啦啦啦 啦啦啦
Tra-la-la-la-la-la Tra-la-la tra-la-la
啦啦啦啦啦啦
Tra-la-la-la-la La-la
从现在起 你会名垂青史
From now on you'll be history
-你会... -你会...
- You'll be his-- - You'll be his--
你就是历史
You'll be history
我们会荣耀你的名字
And we will glorify your name
-为你将制成塑造 -塑像
- You will be a bust - Be a bust
-塑像 -放在名人殿堂中
- Be a bust - In the hall of fame
啦啦啦啦啦啦 啦啦啦 啦啦啦
Tra-la-la-la-la-la Tra-la-la tra-la-la
啦啦啦啦啦啦
Tra-la-la-la-la La-la
啦啦啦啦啦啦 啦啦啦 啦啦啦
Tra-la-la-la-la-la Tra-la-la tra-la-la
啦啦啦啦啦啦
Tra-la-la-la-la La-la
啦啦啦啦啦啦 啦啦啦 啦啦啦
Tra-la-la-la-la-la Tra-la-la tra-la-la
啦啦啦啦啦啦
Tra-la-la-la-la La--
你不是说她已经死了吗
I thought you said she was dead.
死的是她的妹妹 东方坏女巫
That was her sister, the Wicked Witch of the East.
这个是西方坏女巫 她比另一个更坏
This is the Wicked Witch of the West. She's worse than the other one was.
谁杀了我妹妹 谁杀了东方女巫
Who killed my sister? Who killed the Witch of the East?
是你吗
Was it you?
不 那是个意外 我不是有意杀人的
No. No, it was an accident. I didn't mean to kill anybody.
好吧 我的小美人 我也能做出这种意外
Well, my little pretty, I can cause accidents too.
-你忘了红宝石仙鞋了吗 -仙鞋 对了
- Aren't you forgetting the ruby slippers? - The slippers. Yes.
仙鞋
The slippers.
它们不见了
They're gone.
红宝石仙鞋 你对它们做了什么
The ruby slippers. What have you done with them?
快还给我 否则我会...
Give them back to me or I'll--
太迟了 它们就在这里 穿得好好的
It's too late. There they are, and there they'll stay.
把仙鞋还给我 只有我知道怎么使用它
Give me back my slippers. Only I know how to use them.
它对你毫无用处 把它还给我 还给我
They're of no use to you. Give them back to me. Give them back.
好好穿着别脱掉 仙鞋的魔法一定很强大
Keep tight inside of them. Their magic must be powerful...
不然她不会这么急着要回去
...or she wouldn't want them so badly.
少管闲事 葛琳达 否则我也会收拾你
Stay out of this, Glinda, or I'll fix you as well.
太可笑了 在这里你根本没法力
Oh, rubbish! You have no power here.
快走吧 免得又有房子压到你
Begone, before somebody drops a house on you too.
好吧 我会等待时机
Very well. I'll bide my time.
至于你 小美人 没错 我现在没法收拾你
And as for you, it's true I can't attend to you here and now as I'd like.
但最好别让我碰上
But just try to stay out of my way.
给我小心点
Just try.
我会抓住你的 小美人
I'll get you, my pretty...
还有你的小狗
...and your little dog too.
没事了 你们可以起来了 她已经走了
It's all right. You can get up. She's gone.
没事了 你们全都起来吧
It's all right. You can all get up.
多难闻的硫磺味
Oh. What a smell of sulfur.
恐怕你已经成为西方坏女巫的敌人了
I'm afraid you've made an enemy of the Wicked Witch of the West.
你越早离开绿野仙境 就会睡得越安稳 亲爱的
The sooner you get out of Oz altogether, the safer you'll sleep, my dear.
我会不惜一切代价离开绿野仙境
Oh, I'd give anything to get out of Oz altogether.
但是我该怎样回到堪萨斯 我无法按原路返回
But which is the way back to Kansas? I can't go the way I came.
这倒是真的 唯一可能知道路的...
No, that's true. The only person who might know...
是仙境里最伟大的魔法师
...would be the great and wonderful Wizard of Oz himself.
仙境魔法师 他是好人还是坏人
The Wizard of Oz? Is he good or is he wicked?
人很好 但是很神秘
Oh, very good, but very mysterious.
他住在翡翠城 离这里很远
He lives in the Emerald City, a long journey from here.
你带扫帚了吗
Did you bring your broomstick with you?
-没有 恐怕没有 -那么 你得走路了
- No, I'm afraid I didn't. - Well, then, you'll have to walk.
芒奇金人会把你安全地送到芒奇金的边界
The Munchkins will see you safely to the border of Munchkinland.
记住 绝对不要脱下红宝石仙鞋
And remember, never let those ruby slippers off your feet for a moment...
否则你就要受西方邪恶女巫的控制
...or you will be at the mercy of the Wicked Witch of the West.
但是我怎么走到翡翠城
But how do I start for Emerald City?
最好还是从头开始
It's always best to start at the beginning.
你只要顺着黄砖路走
And all you do is follow the Yellow Brick Road.
-但是如果我... -只要顺着黄砖路走
- But what happens if I-- - Just follow the Yellow Brick Road.
再见
Goodbye.
我的天
My.
这里的人来来去去这么快
People come and go so quickly here.
顺着黄砖路走
Follow the Yellow Brick Road
顺着走 顺着走 顺着走 顺着走 顺着黄砖路走
Follow follow follow follow Follow the Yellow Brick Road
顺着黄砖路走 顺着黄砖路走
Follow the Yellow Brick follow the Yellow Brick
顺着黄砖路走
Follow the Yellow Brick Road
你要去见魔法师 绿野仙境里伟大的魔法师
You're off to see the Wizard The wonderful Wizard of Oz
你会发现 他是有史以来最伟大
You'll find he is a whiz of a wiz If ever a wiz there was
如果世上有伟大的魔法师 绿野仙境的魔法师就是其一
If ever oh ever a wiz there was The Wizard of Oz is one because
因为 因为 因为 因为 因为
Because because because Because because
因为他做了许多奇妙的事
Because of the wonderful things he does
你要去见魔法师 绿野仙境里伟大魔法师
You're off to see the Wizard The wonderful Wizard of Oz
顺着黄砖路走
Follow the Yellow Brick Road?
顺着黄砖...
Follow the Yellow...?
现在到底该走那条路
Now which way do we go?
对不起 那条路很好
Pardon me. That way is a very nice way.
是谁在说话
Who said that?
别傻了 托托
Don't be silly, Toto.
-稻草人不会说话 -走那条路也很舒服
- Scarecrows don't talk. - It's pleasant down that way too.
真奇怪 他不是指着另一边吗
That's funny. Wasn't he pointing the other way?
当然有的人会两条路都走
Of course, people do go both ways.
你真的会说话呢
Why, you did say something, didn't you?
你是故意这样做 还是你拿不定主意
Are you doing that on purpose, or can't you make up your mind?
问题就是这个 我拿不定主意
That's the trouble. I can't make up my mind.
我没有头脑
I haven't got a brain.
只有稻草
Only straw.
如果你没头脑怎么会说话
How can you talk if you haven't got a brain?
我不知道
I don't know.
但是有些人没头脑也很会说话
But some people without brains do a lot of talking, don't they?
对 你说得对
Yes, I guess you're right.
我们还没正式见面 对吧
Well, we haven't really met properly, have we?
还没有
Why, no.
-你好 -你好吗
- How do you do? - How do you do?
-我很好 谢谢 -我可是一点也不好
- Very well, thank you. - Oh, I'm not feeling at all well.
整天背着杆子被困在这里太乏味了
It's very tedious being stuck up here all day long with a pole up your back.
我的天 那肯定很不舒服 你不能下来吗
Oh, dear. That must be terribly uncomfortable. Can't you get down?
下来 不行 你看我...
Down? No, you see, I'm-- Well, I'm--
来 让我来帮你
Oh, well, here. Let me help you.
你真是太好了 真好
Oh, that's very kind of you. Very kind.
我的天 我不知道我怎么样...
Oh, dear. I don't see how I can--
当然 我做事情不够聪明...
Of course, I'm not bright about doing things...
但如果你把钉子弯下来 也许我就能滑下来 然后...
...but if you'll just bend the nail down, maybe I'll slip off and--
对了
Oh, yes.
哎哟
Whoops!
-又掉出来了一些 -伤到你了吗
-There goes some of me again. - Does it hurt you?
没事 我只要捡起来再放回去就好了
Oh,no.I just keep picking it up and putting it back in again.
我的天 自由真好
My! It's good to be free!
我吓到你了吗
Did I scare you?
没有 我以为你受伤了
No, no. I just thought you hurt yourself.
-你没吓到吗 -当然没有
- But I didn't scare you? - No, of course not.
我想也是
I didn't think so.
砰 快走开 砰
Boo. Scat. Boo.
你看到了吗 我连乌鸦都吓不了
You see? I can't even scare a crow.
它老远赶来吃我田里的东西 当面嘲笑我
They come from miles around just to eat in my field and laugh in my face.
我是个失败者 因为我没有头脑
Oh, I'm a failure, because I haven't got a brain.
如果你有头脑 你要做什么
Well, what would you do with a brain if you had one?
做什么 如果我有个头脑 我就会...
Do? Why, if I had a brain, I could--
我可以消磨时间与花交谈
I could while away the hours Conferring with the flowers
和雨讨论天气
Consulting with the rain
我会抓抓发痒的头皮 思绪可以源源不断
And my head I'd be scratchin' While my thoughts were busy hatchin'
只要我有头脑
If I only had a brain
我会为解开每个谜语
I'd unravel every riddle For any individ'le
为每个有烦恼或痛苦的人
In trouble or in pain
有这么好的想法 你能成为另一个林肯
With the thoughts you'd be thinkin' You could be another Lincoln
只要你有头脑
If you only had a brain
我可以告诉你为什么
Oh, I could tell you why
海洋靠近海岸
The ocean's near the shore
我能想到从未想过的事情
I could think of things I never thunk before
然后我会坐下来思考更多
And then I'd sit And think some more
我将不再一无所有 我的脑子里充满了东西
I would not be just a nothin' My head all full of stuffin'
我的心充满了痛苦
My heart all full of pain
我会跳舞 快乐的生活将是一场狂欢
I would dance and be merry Life would be a ding-a-derry
只要我有头脑
If I only had a brain
哇哦
Whoa!
太好了
Wonderful.
如果我们堪萨斯的稻草人能够做到...
Why, if our scarecrow back in Kansas could do that...
-乌鸦早就被吓死了 -真的吗
- ...the crows would be scared to pieces. - They would?
-堪萨斯在哪里 -那是我住的地方
- Where's Kansas? - That's where I live.
我太想回去了 所以我要去翡翠城...
I wanna get back there so badly, I'm going to Emerald City...
请绿野仙境魔法师帮我
...to get the Wizard of Oz to help me.
-你要去见魔法师 -嗯哼
- You're going to see a wizard? - Mm-hmm.
你认为我跟你去见魔法师 他会给我头脑吗
Do you think if I went, this wizard would give me brains?
我也不知道
I couldn't say.
但就算他不给 你也不会比现在更糟
But even if he didn't, you'd be no worse off than you are now.
-是啊 这倒是真的 -你最好别跟我去
- Yes, that's true. - But maybe you better not.
我惹怒个女巫 你可能会遇上麻烦
I've got a witch mad at me, and you might get into trouble.
女巫 我才不怕女巫 我什么都不怕
Witch? I'm not afraid of a witch. I'm not afraid of anything.
-除了点燃的火柴 -我想也是
- Except a lighted match. - I don't blame you for that.
为了得到头脑 我愿意面对整盒火柴
But I'd face a whole box of them for the chance of getting some brains.
听着 我不会给你添麻烦 因为我什么都不吃
Look, I won't be any trouble, because I don't eat a thing.
我不会想去管什么事 因为我不会思考
And I won't try to manage things, because I can't think.
你不愿意带我一起去吗
Won't you take me with you?
我当然愿意
of course I will.
太好了 我们一起去见魔法师
Hooray! We're off to see a wizard!
你还不太会走路
You're not starting out very well.
我会努力学习走路 真的
Oh, I'll try. Really, I will.
-去绿野仙境 -去绿野仙境
- To Oz? - To Oz.
我们出发去见魔法师
We're off to see the Wizard
绿野仙境的魔法师
The wonderful Wizard of Oz
我们听说他是前所未有 法师中的法师
We hear he is a whiz of a wiz If ever a wiz there was
前所未有 前所未有的魔法师
If ever, oh ever a wiz there was The Wizard of Oz is one because
因为 因为 因为 因为 因为
Because because because Because because
因为他有极为奇妙的法力
Because of the wonderful things he does
我们出发去见魔法师 绿野仙境里伟大魔法师
We're off to see the wizard The wonderful Wizard of Oz
哦
Oh.
苹果
Apples.
你看
Oh, look.
哦
Oh.
啊哟
Ouch!
你认为你在干什么
What do you think you're doing?
我们走了很长的路 我饿了
We've been walking a long ways and I was hungry and--
你在说话吗
Did you say something?
-她饿了 -她饿了
- She was hungry. - She was hungry.
你喜欢让人过来摘你的东西吗
How would like to have someone come along and pick something off of you?
我的天 我总是忘记这里不是堪萨斯
Oh, dear. I keep forgetting I'm not in Kansas.
走吧 多萝西
Come along, Dorothy.
你不会喜欢这种苹果
You don't want any of those apples. Hmm.
你暗示我的苹果不应该是这样吗
Are you hinting my apples aren't what they ought to be?
不知道 但她不喜欢小绿虫
Oh, no. It's just that she doesn't like little green worms.
你
Oh, you.
我教你怎么得到苹果
I'll show you how to get apples.
哦
Oh! Oh!
太好了 就要它这样 自己捡吧
Hooray! I guess that did it. Help yourself.
是个人呢
Why, it's a man.
用锡做的人
A man made out of tin.
没错
Yes.
看
Look.
你在说话吗
Did you say something?
他在说 "油壶"
He said "oilcan."
-什么油壶 -油壶
- Oil can what? - Oilcan?
在这里
Oh, here it is.
你想先在哪里加油
Where do you want to be oiled first?
他说他的嘴
He said his mouth.
另一边
The other side.
嗯...嗯...嗯...
Mm... Mm... Mm...
我的天哪 我又可以说话了
My goodness. I can talk again. Oh.
请给我的胳膊加油  胳膊肘也要加
Oil my arms, please. Oil my elbows.
这里
Here.
-疼吗 -不疼 感觉好极了
- Did that hurt? - No, it feels wonderful.
我举了那把斧子好长时间了
I've held that ax up for ages.
天哪 你怎么会变成这样
Goodness. How did you ever get like this?
大约一年前
Well, about a year ago...
我正在砍那棵树
...I was chopping that tree...
突然下起雨来
...when suddenly it began to rain.
就在砍的一半时 我就锈住了
And right in the middle of a chop, I rusted solid.
从那以后我就一直这样
And I've been that way ever since.
现在你都好了
Well, you're perfect now.
我的脖子 我的脖子
My neck. My neck.
都好了
Perfect?
敲敲我的胸脯 看我是不是都好了
Bang on my chest if you think I'm perfect.
来吧 敲敲看
Go ahead, bang on it.
没错 还有响亮的回音
Beautiful. What an echo.
它是空的
It's empty.
锡匠忘了给我一颗心
The tinsmith forgot to give me a heart.
-没有心 -没有心
- No heart? - No heart?
没有心
No heart.
都是空的
All hollow.
当一个人有了身份
When a man's an empty kettle
他应该感到精神焕发
He should be on his mettle
但我却无所适从
And yet I'm torn apart
因为我以为自己是人类
Just because I'm presumin' That I could be kind of human
只要我有颗心
If I only had a heart
我会善良 我会温柔 而且多愁善感
I'd be tender, I'd be gentle And awful sentimental
关注爱情和艺术
Regarding love and art
我会成为麻雀和射箭的男孩丘比特的朋友
I'd be friends with the sparrows And the boy who shoots the arrows
只要我有颗心
If I only had a heart
想想我置身阳台下
Picture me A balcony
上面有人低声吟唱
Above, a voice sings low
你在哪里 罗密欧
Wherefore art thou, Romeo?
我听到心跳
I hear a beat
多么甜蜜
How sweet!
只要有这种感觉 妒忌 忠诚
Just to register emotion Jealousy, devotion
真的感觉到了
And really feel the part
我可以保持年轻和爽朗 我会用拉链锁住它
I could stay young and chipper And I'd lock it with a zipper
只要我有颗心
If I only had a heart
哦 哦哦哦哦
Oh! Oh, oh, oh, oh.
-你没事吧 -看来我又生锈了
- Are you all right? - I'm a little rusty yet.
我的天
Oh, dear.
你真了不起
That was wonderful.
知道吗 你可以和我们一起...
You know, we were wondering why you couldn't come with us...
去翡翠城向魔法师要一颗心
...to the Emerald City to ask the Wizard of Oz for a heart.
如果我们到了那里魔法师不给我
Suppose the Wizard wouldn't give me one when we got there.
他会给
Oh, but he will.
他一定会给
He must.
我们已经走了这么远的路
We've come such a long way already.
你说这样就很远了 你才刚刚开始呢
You call that long? Why, you've just begun.
先生们 你们是不是想帮助那个小女孩
Helping the little lady along, are you, my fine gentlemen?
离她远点
Well, stay away from her...
否则我拿你来塞床垫
...or I'll stuff a mattress with you.
还有你
And you.
我把你拿来做巢箱
I'll use you for a beehive.
给你 稻草人 想玩球吗
Here, scarecrow. Wanna play ball?
火 我着火了 我着火了 把它弄走
Fire! I'm burning! I'm burning! Take it away.
我才不怕她
I'm not afraid of her.
不管能不能得到头脑 我会安全的送你到仙境去
I'll see you get safely to the Wizard, whether I get a brain or not.
想拿我塞床垫 哼
Stuff a mattress with me.
不管我能不能得到一颗心 我也会送你到仙境去
I'll see you reach the Wizard, whether I get a heart or not.
巢箱 呸
Beehive. Bah.
让她试试怎么把我做成巢箱
Let her try and make a beehive out of me.
你们真的是我最好的朋友
Oh, you're the best friends anybody ever had.
真奇怪 我觉得我像早就认识你们了
And it's funny, but I feel as if I've known you all the time.
-但那是不可能的 对吧 -我不知道
- But I couldn't have, could I? - I don't see how.
当我被塞满缝起来时 你不在我身边 对吧
You weren't around when I was stuffed and sewn together, were you?
我站在那里生锈了很长时间
And I was standing over there rusting for the longest time.
不过 我还是希望我能记起来
Still, I wish I could remember.
但我想这没关系 我们现在认识了 对吧
But I guess it doesn't matter anyway. We know each other now, don't we?
-没错 -对啊
- That's right. - We do.
-到绿野仙境 -到绿野仙境去
- To Oz? - To Oz.
我们出发去见魔法师
We're off to see the Wizard
绿野仙境里最伟大的魔法师
The wonderful Wizard of Oz
我们听说他是前所未有 法师中的法师
We hear he is a whiz of a wiz If ever a wiz there was
如果世上有伟大的法师存在 绿野仙境的法师就是其一
If ever, oh ever a wiz there was The Wizard of Oz is one because
因为 因为 因为 因为 因为
Because, because, because Because, because
因为他做了很多奇妙的事情
Because of the wonderful things he does
我们要出发去见魔法师 绿野仙境里最伟大的法师
We're off to see the Wizard The wonderful Wizard of Oz
我不喜欢这个森林
I don't like this forest.
这里又黑又恐怖
It's dark and creepy.
虽然我不了解 但我想在它变亮之前会变得更暗
Of course, I don't know, but I think it'll get darker before it gets lighter.
你...
Do...
你认为我们会碰到什么野兽吗
Do you suppose we'll meet any wild animals?
有可能
We might.
有吃稻草的野兽吗
Animals that eat straw?
有一些 但主要是狮子 老虎和熊
Some, but mostly lions and tigers and bears.
-狮子 -还有老虎
- Lions. - And tigers?
和熊
And bears.
狮子 老虎和熊
Lions and tigers and bears.
我的天
Oh, my.
狮子 老虎和熊
Lions and tigers and bears.
我的天
Oh, my.
狮子 老虎和熊
Lions and tigers and bears.
我的天
Oh, my.
狮子 老虎和熊
Lions and tigers and bears.
我的天
Oh, my.
狮子 老虎和熊
Lions and tigers and bears.
我的天
Oh, my.
看
Oh, look.
来啊 来啊
Put 'em up. Put 'em up.
哪个要先来
Which one of you first?
如果愿意你们两个可以一起来
I'll fight you both together, if you want.
我可以一只爪子放在背后和你们打
I'll fight you with one paw tied behind my back.
也可以一只脚站着和你们打
I'll fight you standing on one foot.
我闭上眼睛和你们打
I'll fight you with my eyes closed.
想拿斧头砍我是不是
Oh, pulling an ax on me, eh?
想偷袭我吗 嗯...
Sneaking up on me, eh? Why...
-走开 让我一个人待着 -害怕了
- Here, here. Go away and let us alone. - Oh, scared, huh?
怕我了 嗯
Afraid, huh?
你在那个罐子里能保鲜多久
How long can you stay fresh in that can?
来吧 站起来打啊 你这个发抖的废物
Come on, get up and fight, you shivering junkyard.
把手举起来 你这个草包袋
Put your hands up, you lopsided bag of hay.
你这是人身攻击 狮子
That's getting personal, Lion.
对 起来教训它一顿
Yes, get up and teach him a lesson.
你去教训他不更好吗
What's wrong with you teaching him?
我几乎不认识他
Well, I hardly know him.
不管怎样我都会抓到你 小家伙
Well, I'll get you anyway, peewee.
你真不要脸
Shame on you.
你为什么打我 我又没咬它
What did you do that for? I didn't bite him.
不 你想去咬啊
No, but you tried to.
捉弄稻草人已经够差劲了 又想吓我可怜的小狗...
It's bad enough picking on a straw man, but picking on poor little dogs...
那你也不必打我啊 是吧
Well, you didn't have to go and hit me, did you?
我的鼻子流血了吗
Is my nose bleeding?
当然没有
Well, of course not.
我的天 你可真会小题大做
My goodness, what a fuss you're making.
你当然会到处找比你弱的东西...
Well, naturally, when you go around picking on things weaker than you are...
原来你不过是个胆小鬼
You're nothing but a big coward.
你说对了 我是个胆小鬼
You're right, I am a coward.
我一点胆量都没有
I haven't any courage at all.
我甚至害怕自己
I even scare myself.
你看我的黑眼圈
Look at the circles under my eyes.
我已经好几个周没睡觉了
I haven't slept in weeks.
你为什么不试试数羊呢
Why don't you try counting sheep?
那没用 我连羊都怕
That doesn't do any good. I'm afraid of them.
太可怜了
Oh, that's too bad.
你不觉得魔法师可以帮他吗
Don't you think the Wizard could help him too?
我想没什么不可以的
I don't see why not.
跟我们一起去
Come along with us.
我们正要去见魔法师 给他一颗心
We're on our way to see the Wizard. To get him a heart.
-还有他的头脑 -他可以给你点胆量
- And him a brain. - He could give you some courage.
有个胆小的狮子陪伴 你会不会觉得丢脸
Wouldn't you feel degraded to be seen in the company of a cowardly lion?
我会
I would.
不 当然不会
No, of course not.
你们太好了
Gee, that's awfully nice of you.
-我的生活让人难以忍受 -噢
- My life has been simply unbearable. - Oh.
好了 现在没事了
Well, it's all right now.
魔法师会解决所有问题
The Wizard'll fix everything.
它在我心里已经很久了
It's been in me so long.
我只想告诉你我内心的感受
I just gotta tell you how I feel.
那我们走吧
Well, come on.
相信我 这很可悲 小姐
Yeah, it's sad, Believe me, missy
当你生来就胆小如鼠时
When you're born to be a sissy
没有活力和激情
Without the vim and verve
我可以证明我的勇猛是狮子 不是老鼠
But I could show my prowess Be a lion, not a mouse
只要我有胆量
If I only had the nerve
恐怕没有人否认 我是一只雄狮
I'm afraid there's no denyin' I'm just a dandy lion
可怜造化弄人
A fate I don't deserve
-我会意气风发 -我会温柔有心
- I'd be brave as a blizzard - I'd be gentle as a lizard
我会足智多谋
I'd be clever as a gizzard
只要魔法师愿意使出法力
If the Wizard is a wizard Who will serve
那我就能得到头脑
Then I'm sure to get a brain
-一个心 -回家
- A heart - A home
有胆量
The nerve!
哦
Oh
我们一起去见魔法师 绿野仙境里伟大的法师
We're off to see the Wizard The wonderful Wizard of Oz
听说他是前所未有 法师中的法师
We hear he is a whiz of a wiz If ever a wiz there was
如果世上有伟大的法师存在 绿野仙境法师就是
If ever, oh ever a wiz there was The Wizard of Oz is one because
因为 因为 因为 因为 因为
Because, because, because Because, because
因为他做了许多奇妙的事情
Because of the wonderful things he does
我们一起去见魔法师 绿野仙境里伟大的法师
We're off to see the Wizard The wonderful Wizard of Oz
看来你们是不听从警告
So you won't take warning, eh?
那么就要大难临头
All the worse for you, then.
我现在就来收拾你们 而不是以后
I'll take care of you now instead of later.
等我得到那双红宝石仙鞋
When I gain those ruby slippers...
我的法力就是绿野仙境最强大的
...my power will be the greatest in Oz.
现在 小美人...
And now, my beauties...
这是有毒的东西
...something with poison in it, I think.
里面有毒
With poison in it.
但看着非常迷人 舒缓的气味
But attractive to the eye and soothing to the smell.
罂粟花
Poppies.
罂粟花会让他们入睡
Poppies will put them to sleep.
睡吧
Sleep...
现在他们要睡觉了
Now they'll sleep.
那就是翡翠城
There's Emerald City.
我们终于快到了
Oh, we're almost there. At last. At last.
它很漂亮 对不对 就像我想的那样
It's beautiful, isn't it? Just like I knew it would be.
能住在那么美的城市里 一定是个了不起的魔法师
He really must be a wonderful wizard to live in a city like that.
走啊 我们还等什么
Come on, what are we waiting for?
-很好 我们快走 -对 我们跑吧
- Nothing. Let's hurry. - Yes, let's run.
-快点 快点 -快 快
- Come on. Come on. - Hurry. Hurry.
你看
Oh, look.
快来 快来
Come on. Come on.
看这景色 太美了
Look at the scenery. It's wonderful.
翡翠城
Emerald City.
怎么回事
Oh. What's happening?
为什么
What is it?
我跑不动了
I can't run anymore.
-我太困了 -把你的手给我们 我们拉着你走
- I'm so sleepy. - Give us your hands and we'll pull you.
不 请不要 我得休息一下
Oh, no, please. I have to rest for just a minute.
托托 托托在哪里
Toto. Where's Toto?
你现在不能休息 我们快到了
You can't rest now. We're nearly there.
别哭了 你会再次生锈的
Don't cry. You'll rust yourself again.
想想看 眨四十下眼睛打个盹也不错
Coming to think of it, forty winks wouldn't be bad.
-你不要也开始这样 -别
- Don't you start it too. - No.
我们应该背着多萝西
We ought to carry Dorothy.
我可能不行 但可以试试
I don't think I could, but we could try.
-好 -对
- Let's. - Yes.
-你看他 太糟糕了 -来 锡人 帮帮我
- Now look at him. This is terrible. - Here, Tin Man, help me.
太可怕了 我一点也挪不动她
Oh, this is terrible. I can't budge her an inch.
这是个魔法 这是...
This is a spell, this is.
是那个坏女巫干的 我们该怎么办
It's the Wicked Witch. What'll we do?
救命
Help! Help!
在这种时候喊叫是没有用的
It's no use screaming at a time like this.
没有人会听见 救命啊
Nobody will hear you! Help! Help!
救命
Help!
下起雪来了
It's snowing.
不会吧
No, it isn't.
是下雪了
Yes, it is.
也许这会有用
Maybe that'll help.
但这也没用
Oh, but it couldn't help.
确实有用 多萝西 你醒来了
It does help. Dorothy, you're waking up.
哦哦
Oh. Oh.
这种天气很不寻常 不是吗
Unusual weather we're having, ain't it?
看 他又生锈了
Look. He's rusted again.
-快把油壶给我 -给你 天哪
- Oh, give me the oilcan, quick. - Here. Oh, dear.
-他又锈住了 -这里
- He is rusted. - Here.
-给你 -快点
- Here. - Quick. Oh. Oh.
该死 该死
Curses! Curses!
总是有人帮助那女孩
Somebody always helps that girl.
但不管是否鞋 我都有足够的力量征服她
But shoes or no shoes, I'm still great enough to conquer her.
那些阻止我的人灾难临头了
And woe to those who try to stop me.
来吧 我们离开这里
Come on, let's get out of here.
看 翡翠城比以往更近更漂亮
Look. Emerald City is closer and prettier than ever.
你已经走出了森林
You're out of the woods
你走出了黑暗 你走出了夜晚
You're out of the dark You're out of the night
踏进阳光 踏入光明
Step into the sun Step into the light
直接向前 朝着光荣之地
Keep straight ahead for The most glorious place
不论在地上或是在天上
On the face of the earth Or the sky
保持你的呼吸 握住你的心
Hold on to your breath Hold on to your heart
坚守你的希望
Hold on to your hope
向大门走去 将它打开
March up to the gate And bid it open
去翡翠城 快如闪电
To the Emerald City, as fast as lightning.
你已经走出了森林
You're out of the woods
你走出了黑暗 你走出了夜晚
You're out of the dark You're out of the night
踏进阳光 踏入光明
Step into the sun Step into the light
向大门走去 将它打开
March up to the gate And bid it
打开
Open
谁敲的钟
Who rang that bell?
-是我们 -你们不识字吗
- We did. - Can't you read?
-识什么字 -公告啊
- Read what? - The notice.
-什么公告 -在门上的
- What notice? - It's on the door.
就像我脸上的鼻子一样明显
As plain as the nose on my face.
哦... 嗯...
Oh... Uh...
哦 啧 啧 啧
Oh. Tsk, tsk, tsk.
钟
坏了
请敲门
"钟坏了 请敲门"
"Bell out of order. Please knock."
好 这才像话
Well. That's more like it.
现在 说说你们有什么事
Now, state your business.
我们要见魔法师
We wanna see the Wizard.
魔法师
The Wizard?
但是没有人能见魔法师
But nobody can see the great Oz.
没人见过魔法师 甚至我也没见过他
Nobody's ever seen the great Oz. Even I've never seen him.
那你怎么知道有他的存在
Well, then, how do you know there is one?
因为他...
Because he's--
你们在浪费我的时间
Oh! You're wasting my time.
求你 求求你 先生 我必须要见魔法师
Oh, please. Please, sir. I've got to see the Wizard.
-北方的好女巫派我来的 -证明给我看
- The Good Witch of the North sent me. - Prove it.
她穿的红宝石仙鞋就是她送的
She's wearing the ruby slippers that she gave her.
果然是真的 真是有眼不识泰山
Oh! So she is. Well, bust my buttons.
为什么你不早说呢
Why didn't you say that in the first place?
那就是另一回事了
That's a horse of a different color.
进来吧
Come on in.
马车 马车
Cabby. Cabby.
这正是你们要找的 我会带你们去城里的任何地方
Just what you're looking for. Take you any place in the city, we does.
-你能带我们去见魔法师吗 -魔法师 我不能
- Would you take us to see the Wizard? - The Wizard? I can't--
当然可以 但我先要带你们去一个小地方
Yes, of course. But first I'll take you to a little place...
-你们可以梳理一下 -太谢谢你了
...where you can tidy up a bit. - Oh, thank you so much.
我们走了好久的路 感觉身上很脏乱
We've been gone such a long time, and we feel so mess--
这是什么马 我从没见过这样的马
What kind of a horse is that? I've never seen a horse like that before.
以后也看不见了 这是独一无二的马
No, and never will again, I fancy. There's only one of him, and he's it.
它就是你听说过的不同颜色的马
He's the horse of a different color you've heard tell about.
哈 哈 哈 呵 呵 呵
Ha-ha-ha! Ho-ho-ho!
还有一对啦啦啦
And a couple of tra-la-las
这就是我们在绿野仙境里的欢乐时光
That's how we laugh the day away In the merry old land of Oz
吱 吱 吱 恰 恰 恰
Bzz, bzz, bzz! Chirp, chirp, chirp!
还有一对啦啦啦
And a couple of la-di-das
这就是我们在绿野仙境里喧闹的时光
That's how the crickets crick all day In the merry old land of Oz
我们在十二点起床 一点开始工作
We get up at twelve And start to work at one
花一小时吃午饭 在两点吃完饭
Take an hour for lunch And then at two we're done
真好玩
Jolly good fun!
哈 哈 哈 呵 呵 呵
Ha-ha-ha! Ho-ho-ho!
还有一对啦啦啦
And a couple of tra-la-las
这就是我们在绿野仙境里的欢乐时光
That's how we laugh the day away In the merry old land of Oz
哈 哈 哈 呵 呵 呵
Ha-ha-ha! Ho-ho-ho!
哈 哈 哈 哈 哈
Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha!
我们就这样欢乐的笑着度过一天
That's how we laugh the day away With a
洗&刷  公司
呵 呵 呵 哈 哈 哈
Ho-ho-ho! Ha-ha-ha!
在这欢乐的绿野仙境里
In the merry old land of Oz
-补补这里 -补补那里
- Pat, pat here - Pat, pat there
加上一些全新的稻草
And a couple of brand-new straws
这是让你在欢乐的绿野仙境里保持年轻好看
That's how we keep you young and fair In the merry old land of Oz
-擦擦这里 -擦擦那里
- Rub, rub here - Rub, rub there
不管你是锡或铜
Whether you're tin or bronze
这是我们帮你在欢乐的绿野仙境里修补完整
That's how we keep you in repair In the merry old land of Oz
我们可以使皱眉变成笑靥
We can make a dimpled smile Out of a frown
你能把我的眼睛染成和衣裙相配的颜色吗
Can you even dye my eyes To match my gown?
-啊哈 -真了不起
- Uh-huh  - Jolly old town!
剪剪这里 剪剪那里
- Clip, clip here - Clip, clip there
我们做最好的修饰
We give the roughest claws
在欢乐的绿野仙境中 充满智慧才干的气氛
That certain air of savoir-faire In the merry old land of Oz
哈 哈 哈 呵 呵 呵
Ha-ha-ha! Ho-ho-ho!
-哈 哈 哈 -哈
- Ha-ha-ha! - Ha
这就是我们在绿野仙境里的欢乐时光
That's how we laugh the day away In the merry old land of Oz
我们就这样欢乐的笑着度过一天
That's how we laugh the day away With a
-哈 哈 哈 -哈 哈 哈
- Ha-ha-ha! - Ha-ha-ha!
在这欢乐的绿野仙境里
In the merry old land of Oz
她是谁
Who's her? Who's her?
是坏女巫 她跟着我们来了
It's the witch. She's followed us here.
"投降吧 多萝西 "
"Surrender, Dorothy."
多萝西 谁是多萝西
Dorothy? Who's Dorothy?
-魔法师会解释的 -去问魔法师
- The Wizard will explain it. - To the Wizard.
我们该怎么办
Dear. Whatever shall we do?
我们得快去见魔法师
We better hurry if we're gonna see the Wizard.
好了 没事了 一切都没问题了
Here. Here, here. Everything is all right.
别慌 继续...
Stop that now, just--
没事了 一切都没问题了
It's all right. Everything is all right.
伟大和法力无边的魔法师 已经控制局面了
The great and powerful Oz has got matters well in hand.
希望如此
I hope.
你们都可以回家了 没什么好担心的
So you can all go home. There's nothing to worry about.
离开这里 现在回家去吧
Get out of here. Now go on. Go on home.
回家吧
Go home.
我们想马上见到魔法师 我们四个人都要
We want to see the Wizard right away. All four of us.
命令是 没人能见伟大的魔法师 没人 绝不允许
Orders are, nobody can see the great Oz. Not nobody, not nohow.
但是求求你 很重要的事
But, please. It's very important.
为了见魔法师我弄了个烫发
I got a permanent just for the occasion.
任何人都不行
Not nobody, not nohow!
但她就是多萝西
But she's Dorothy.
是女巫指的多萝西
The witch's Dorothy?
嗯 这就不一样了
Well, that makes a difference.
就在这里等着 我马上通知你们
Just wait here. I'll announce you at once.
你听到没 他会马上通知我们
Did you hear that? He'll announce us at once.
-我马上就能得到我的头脑了 -我几乎听到我的心跳了
- I've as good as got my brain. - I can fairly hear my heart beating.
我能赶回家吃晚餐
I'll be home for supper.
再过一个小时 我就是森林之王
In another hour, I'll be king of the forest.
国王万岁
Long live the king.
如果我是森林之王
If I were king of the forest
不是王后
Not queen
不是公爵
Not duke
不是王子
Not prince
我的堂堂森林王袍
My regal robes of the forest
将是缎子
Would be satin
不是棉料
Not cotton
不是印花棉布
Not chintz
我会发号命令 不论是对鱼还是鸟
I'd command each thing Be it fish or fowl
都是一声吼叫
With a woof!
And a woof!
一声皇家咆哮
And a royal growl
当我动一下脚跟 所有的树都会跪下
As I'd click my heel All the trees would kneel
群山低头公牛叩首
And the mountains bow And the bulls kowtow
麻雀们就会展翅飞翔
And the sparrow would take wing
如果我
If I
如果我是国王
If I were king
每只兔子都会向我致敬
Each rabbit would show respect to me
花栗鼠们向我跪拜
The chipmunks genuflect to me
尽管我的尾巴会鞭策我
Though my tail would lash
我仍会显示
I would show compash
我仍会慈悲的对待每个下属
For every underling
如果我
If I
如果我是国王
If I were king
就是国王
Just king
我所知道的君主
Monarch of all I survey
君主
Monarch
我所知道的
Of all I survey
如果你是国王 你就什么都不怕了吗
If you were king, you wouldn't be afraid of anything?
不怕 全都不怕
Not nobody, not nohow!
-连犀牛也不怕 -绝不怕
- Not even a rhinoceros? - Imposserous.
-连河马也不怕 -我会把它敲碎
- How about a hippopotamus? - I'd trash him from top to "bottom-us."
-如果你遇到大象呢 -我会用"玻璃纸"把它包起来
- Supposing you met an elephant? - I'd wrap him up in "cello-phant".
-那么雷龙呢 -我会让它知道谁是森林之王
- What if it were a brontosaurus? - I'd show him who's king of the forest.
-怎么做 -怎么做
- How? - How?
勇气
Courage.
是什么让奴隶变成国王 勇气
What makes a king out of a slave? Courage.
是什么让桅杆上的旗子飘扬 勇气
What makes the flag on the mast to wave? Courage.
是什么让大象高高举它的长牙
What makes the elephant charge his tusk...
是在迷雾或是在昏暗的暮色
...in the misty mist or the dusky dusk?
是什么让麝鼠守卫他的麝香 勇气
What makes the muskrat guard his musk? Courage.
是什么使狮身人面像成为世界七大奇迹 勇气
What makes the sphinx the Seventh Wonder? Courage.
是什么让黎明像雷声一样出现 勇气
What makes the dawn come up like thunder? Courage.
是什么让蛮族人这么火热
What makes the Hottentot so hot?
是什么让"人猿"敢爬上杏树
What puts the "ape" in apricot?
是什么东西他们有而我没有
What have they got that I ain't got?
-勇气 -说得好
- Courage. - You can say that again.
嗯
Huh?
魔法师叫你们走开
The Wizard says go away.
走开
Go away?
看来我们走了这么远 却一无所获
Looks like we came a long way for nothing.
我刚刚还那么高兴
And I was so happy.
我还以为我可以马上回家了
I thought I was on my way home.
别哭 我们会带你去找魔法师
Don't cry. We're gonna get you to the Wizard.
我们一定会
We certainly are.
艾姆婶婶对我那么好...
Auntie Em was so good to me...
我却从来没有感激过
...and I never appreciated it.
反而跑掉 伤她的心
Running away and hurting her feelings.
马维尔教授说她病了
Professor Marvel said she was sick.
她可能快死了
She may be dying...
都是我的错
...and it's all my fault.
我绝对不会原谅自己
I'll never forgive myself.
绝对不会 不会
Never, never, never.
请别再哭了
Please don't cry anymore.
我会想办法让你见到魔法师
I'll get you into the Wizard somehow.
来吧 我自己也有个艾姆婶婶
Come on. I had an Aunt Em myself once.
等一下 伙伴们
Wait a minute, fellas.
我只是在想 我没那么想见魔法师
I was just thinking, I really don't want to see the Wizard this much.
我最好在外面等你们
I better wait for you outside.
-你怎么啦 -他只是又害怕了
- What's the matter? - He's just scared again.
你忘了魔法师会给你勇气吗
Don't you know the Wizard will give you courage?
我太害怕了 不敢向他要
I'd be too scared to ask him for it.
那我们替你找他要
Well, then, we'll ask him for you.
我还是在外面等吧
I'd sooner wait outside.
为什么
Why? Why?
因为我还是很胆小
Because I'm still scared.
-发生了什么事 -有人拉我的尾巴
- What happened? - Somebody pulled my tail.
-你自己拉的 -我
- You did it yourself. - I...
哦 这里
Oh. Here.
来吧
Come on.
向前走
Come forward.
结束的时候告诉我
Tell me when it's over.
你们看 你们看
Look at that. Look at that.
我要回去
I wanna go home.
我是魔法师
I am Oz...
伟大法力无边的
...the great and powerful.
你们是谁
Who are you?
对不起
If you please...
我是多萝西
...I am Dorothy...
卑微又温顺
...the small and meek.
我们特地来求你
We've come to ask you--
-安静 -哦
- Silence! - Oh!
哦 好吓人
Oh! Jiminy crickets.
伟大法力无比的魔法师
The great and powerful Oz...
知道你们为何而来
...knows why you have come.
向前一步
Step forward...
锡人
...Tin Man.
你敢来找我要颗心 是吗
You dare to come to me for a heart, do you?
你这叮当作响的
You clinking, clanking, clattering...
一堆废物组合 无用的东西
...collection of caliginous junk.
是 先生
Yes, sir.
是 阁下
Yes, Your Honor.
你看
You see...
不久前 当我们走在黄砖路上时 然后...
...a while back, we were walking down the Yellow Brick Road and--
安静
Quiet!
而你 稻草人
And you, Scarecrow...
厚颜无耻地想要头脑
...have the effrontery to ask for a brain...
你这滚动的一捆牛饲料
...you billowing bale of bovine fodder.
是的 法官大人 我是说 大人
Yes, Your Honor. I mean, Your Excellency.
我是说 法师大人
I mean, Your Wizardry.
够了
Enough.
还有你 狮子
And you, Lion.
嗯
Well?
你应该为自己感到羞耻
You ought to be ashamed of yourself...
他来找你帮忙 你却这样吓唬他
...frightening him like that when he came to you for help.
安静 自以为是的家伙
Silence, whippersnapper.
仁慈的魔法师愿意答应你们的请求
The beneficent Oz has every intention of granting your requests.
什么 他说什么 嗯 他说什么
What's that? What'd he say? Huh? What'd he say?
但你们必须先完成个小任务
But first, you must prove yourselves worthy...
来证明自己的价值
...by performing a very small task.
把西方女巫的扫帚拿来
Bring me the broomstick of the Witch of the West.
但如果我们要拿到 必须杀了她才行
But if we do that, we'll have to kill her to get it.
把她的扫帚给我...
Bring me her broomstick...
我就会满足你们的请求
...and I'll grant your requests.
现在滚吧
Now go.
如果她先杀了我们呢
But what if she kills us first?
我叫你们滚
I said go!
鬼魂森林
女巫城堡
☜一英里
如果我是你
我就回去!
"如果我是你 我就回去"
"I'd turn back if I were you."
我相信这附近有幽灵
I believe there's spooks around here.
太荒谬了 哪来的幽灵 太傻了
That's ridiculous. Spooks. That's silly.
你不相信有幽灵吗
Don't you believe in spooks?
不是 只是...哦
No. Why, only-- Oh!
你没事吧
Are you all right?
我相信有幽灵 我相信有幽灵 我信 我信 我信 我信
I do believe in spooks. I do believe in spooks. I do, I do, I do, I do.
I do believe in spooks. I do believe in spooks. I do, I do, I do, I do, I do, I do.
在我和你玩够之前 你会相信更多
You'll believe in more than that before I'm finished with you.
带上你的军队 把那女孩和她的狗带给我
Take your army and bring me that girl and her dog.
你可以随意处置其他人 但我要她活着毫发无伤
Do what you like with the others, but I want her alive and unharmed.
我保证他们不会给你惹麻烦
They'll give you no trouble. I promise you that.
我派了一些小昆虫到前面去把他们赶走
I've sent a little insect on ahead to take the fight out of them.
对那双仙鞋要特别小心 那是我最想到的东西
Take special care of those slippers. I want those most of all.
现在 飞 飞吧
Now, fly! Fly!
把那个女孩和她的仙鞋带来
Bring me that girl and her slippers.
飞啊 飞啊 飞啊
Fly! Fly! Fly!
救命 救命
Help! Help!
快走开
Go away now!
托托 托托 救命
Toto! Toto! Help!
救命 救命 救命
Help! Help! Help!
你怎么了
What happened to you?
他们把我的腿扯下来扔在那里
They tore my legs off and threw them over there.
然后他们把我的胸部扔到那里
Then they took my chest and threw it over there.
到处都是你
That's you all over.
他们肯定把你打得够呛
They sure knocked the stuffings out of you.
别站在那看 快把我装起来 我们必须找到多萝西
Don't stand there. Put me together. We've got to find Dorothy.
现在 让我看看...
Now, let's see...
多可爱的小狗
What a nice little dog.
而你 亲爱的 真是意外的惊喜
And you, my dear. What an unexpected pleasure.
在我寂寞的时候 你来找我 真是太好了
It's so kind of you to visit me in my loneliness.
你想把我的狗怎么样 把它还给我
What are you gonna do with my dog? Give him back to me.
等时间到了再说 小美人
All in good time, my little pretty.
-一切都来的很及时 -求求你把狗还给我
- All in good time. - Please give me back my dog.
当然 当然
Certainly, certainly...
当你把仙鞋给我时
...when you give me those slippers.
-但是好女巫让我不要给你 -很好
- But the Good Witch told me not to. - Very well.
把篮子扔进河里淹死它
Throw that basket in the river and drown him.
不 不要 你可以把仙鞋拿去 但托托要还给我
No. Here. You can have your old slippers, but give me back Toto.
是个好女孩
That's a good little girl.
我就知道你很明智
I knew you'd see reason.
对不起 不是我干的 我可以要回我的狗吗
I'm sorry. I didn't do it. Can I still have my dog?
不行 我真傻 我应该记得...
No! Fool that I am, I should have remembered...
只要你还活着...
...those slippers will never come off...
仙鞋就永远脱不下来
...as long as you're alive.
但我担心的不是这个 而是如何去做
But that's not what's worrying me. It's how to do it.
这些事情必须小心处理...
These things must be done delicately...
否则你会伤害咒语
...or you hurt the spell.
-快跑 托托 快跑 -抓住它 你这个笨蛋
-Run, Toto, run! - Catch him, you fool!
快跑 托托 快跑
Run, Toto, run.
它逃掉了 它逃掉了
He got away. He got away.
那么你会更受苦
Which is more than you will.
咒你和你的狗
Drat, you and your dog.
你给我添了这么多麻烦
You've been more trouble to me than you're worth.
但很快就结束了
But it'll soon be over now.
你看到了吗
Do you see that?
你只能活这么多久了
That's how much longer you've got to be alive.
时间不会太久 小美人 不会太久
And it isn't long, my pretty. It isn't long.
我不能永远等着那双鞋
I can't wait forever to get those shoes.
我害怕
I'm frightened.
我害怕 艾姆婶婶 我害怕
I'm frightened, Auntie Em. I'm frightened.
多萝西 多萝西
Dorothy. Dorothy.
你在哪里 是我 是艾姆婶婶
Where are you? It's me. It's Auntie Em.
我们一直在找你 你在哪里
We're trying to find you. Where are you?
我在绿野仙境里 艾姆婶婶
I'm here in Oz, Auntie Em.
我被锁在女巫的城堡里
I'm locked up in the Witch's castle...
我一直设法回家找你 艾姆婶婶
...and I'm trying to get home to you, Auntie Em.
艾姆婶婶 别走开
Oh, Auntie Em, don't go away.
我很害怕 回来 回来
I'm frightened. Come back. Come back.
"艾姆婶婶 艾姆婶婶 回来"
"Auntie Em, Auntie Em. Come back."
我会把艾姆婶婶给你 小美人
I'll give you Auntie Em, my pretty.
看 托托来了 他从哪里来的
Look. There's Toto. Where'd he come from?
哎 你还不明白吗 他是来带我们去找多萝西
Why, don't you see? He's come to take us to Dorothy.
快走 伙伴们
Come on, fellas.
我希望我的力量能坚持下去
I hope my strength holds out.
希望你的尾巴能撑得住
I hope your tail holds out.
那是什么 那是什么
What's that? What's that?
那是坏女巫的城堡
That's the castle of the Wicked Witch.
-多萝西在那个可怕的地方 -我真不希望她在里面
- Dorothy's in that awful place? - I hate to think of her in there.
-我们得把她救出来 -现在别哭
- We've got to get her out. - Don't cry now.
我们没带油壶 而你已经够吵的了
We haven't got the oilcan, and you've been squeaking enough as it is.
他们是谁 他们是谁
Who's them? Who's them?
-我有个进去的办法 -好 他有办法了
- I've got a plan how to get in there. - Fine. He's got a plan.
-你要带领我们 -对
- And you're gonna lead us. - Yeah.
-我 -对 就是你
- Me? - Yes, you.
-我要把她救出来 -没错
- I gotta get her out of there? - That's right.
好吧 为了多萝西 我进去
All right, I'll go in there for Dorothy.
不管有没有坏女巫...
Wicked Witch or no Wicked Witch...
不管有没有警卫 我都要把他们撕成碎片
...guards or no guards, I'll tear them apart.
我也许不能活着出来 但我要进去
I may not come out alive, but I'm going in there.
我只需要让你们做一件事
There's only one thing I want you to do.
-是什么 -是什么
- What's that? - What's that?
劝我别这么做
Talk me out of it.
-不行 你不能走 -别走
- No, you don't. - Oh, no.
-等一下 -上
- Now, wait a minute. - Up.
嘘
Shh!
嘘 嘘
Shh! Shh!
把他们放起来
Put 'em up.
来吧 我有另一个办法了
Come on, I've got another idea.
你认为这样顺道进去够礼貌吗
Do you think it would be polite, dropping in like this?
来吧 来吧
Come on. Come on.
-我们现在去哪里 -是啊
- Where do we go now? - Yeah.
那边
There.
等等 我们最好先确认一下 多萝西 你在里面吗
Wait. We better make sure. Dorothy, are you in there?
-是我们 -我在
- It's us. - Yes.
是我 我被锁在里面了
It's me. She's locked me in.
我们得把她救出来 快开门
We gotta get her out. Open the door.
快点 请快点
Oh, hurry. Please hurry.
沙漏快流光了
The hourglass is almost empty.
往后退
Stand back.
托托 托托 狮子
Oh, Toto. Toto. Oh, Lion.
-我就知道你们会来 我就知道你们会的 -多萝西
- I knew you'd come. I knew you would. - Dorothy.
快走 我们不能再浪费时间了
Hurry, we've got no time to lose.
这么快就要走了 我可不愿意
Going so soon? I wouldn't hear of it.
我的小派对才刚刚开始
Why, my little party's just beginning.
被困了 像老鼠一样被困住
Trapped. Trapped like mice...rats.
对了 不要伤害他们
That's right. Don't hurt them right away.
我会让他们先考虑一下
We'll let them think about it a little first.
抓住他们 抓住他们
Seize them! Seize them!
拦住他们 你们这些蠢货
Stop them, you fools!
抓住他们 抓住他们
Seize them! Seize them!
去找他们 快去找到他们
There they go. Now we've got them.
一半人往这边走 一半人往那边走
Half of you go this way, half of you go that way.
快 快
Hurry. Hurry!
我们现在要往哪里走
Where do we go now?
这边走 快点
This way. Come on.
回去 退回去
Back. Back.
嗯
Well.
玫瑰花环周围 一个装满长矛的口袋
Ring around the rosie, a pocket full of spears.
你以为你们很聪明 是不是
Thought you'd be pretty foxy, didn't you?
最后一个死的 将看到前三个比她先走
The last to go will see the first three go before her.
还有她那肮脏的小狗
And her mangy little dog too.
来点火怎么样 稻草人
How about a little fire, Scarecrow?
别 别 别
No! No! No!
救命 我着火了 我着火了 救命
Help! I'm burning! I'm burning! It's burning! Help!
别泼水
Don't throw that water!
你这天生的扫帚星 看你干的好事
You cursed brat! Look what you've done!
我在融化 融化了
I'm melting! Melting!
这是什么世界 这是什么世界
Oh, what a world! What a world!
谁会想到像你这样的好女孩
Who would've thought a good little girl like you...
可以毁灭我美好的邪恶
...could destroy my beautiful wickedness?
看啊 看啊
Look out! Look out!
我要完了
I'm going.
她死了 你杀了她
She's dead. You've killed her.
我不是故意要杀她 真的 我不是
I didn't mean to kill her. Really, I didn't.
只是因为他着火了
It's just that he was on fire.
多萝西万岁 邪恶的女巫死了
Hail to Dorothy. The Wicked Witch is dead.
万岁 多萝西万岁 邪恶的女巫死了
Hail. Hail to Dorothy. The Wicked Witch is dead.
扫帚
The broom.
-可以给我们吗 -请 你可以把它带走
- May we have it? - Please. And take it with you.
太感谢你了
Oh, thank you so much.
现在我们可以回仙境告诉魔法师 恶女巫已经死了
Now we can go tell the Wizard the Wicked Witch is dead.
邪恶的女巫死了
The Wicked Witch is dead.
我能相信我的眼睛吗
Can I believe my eyes?
你们为什么又回来了
Why have you come back?
法师 我们按照你说的完成了
Please, sir. We've done what you told us.
我们给你带来了西方恶女巫的扫帚
We've brought you the broomstick of the Wicked Witch of the West.
我们融化了她
We melted her.
你们把她干掉了
Ah, you liquidated her, eh?
-非常机智 -是 法师
- Very resourceful. - Yes, sir.
所以我们希望你能信守诺言 法师
So we'd like you to keep your promise to us, if you please, sir.
没那么快 没这么快
Not so fast. Not so fast!
我得仔细考虑一下这件事
I'll have to give the matter a little thought.
走吧 明天再来
Go away and come back tomorrow.
明天 但我现在就想回家
Tomorrow? Oh, but I wanna go home now.
-你已经有足够的时间考虑 -是啊
- You've had plenty of time already. - Yeah.
别激怒伟大法力无边的魔法师
Do not arouse the wrath of the great and powerful Oz.
我说了明天再来
I said come back tomorrow.
如果你真的伟大法力无边 你就应该信守诺言
If you were really great and powerful, you'd keep your promises.
你竟敢指责伟大的魔法师
Do you presume to criticize the great Oz?
你们这些忘恩负义的家伙
You ungrateful creatures.
你们应该觉得自己很幸运 我明天再见你们
Think yourselves lucky that I'm giving you audience tomorrow...
而不是二十年后
...instead of 20 years from now.
哦
Oh!
伟大的魔法师已经说了
The great Oz has spoken. Oh!
别理窗帘后面的那个人
Pay no attention to that man behind the curtain.
伟大的魔法师已经说了
The great and-- Oz has spoken.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是伟大法力无边的绿野仙境魔法师
I am the great and powerful Wizard of Oz.
是你 我不相信
You are? I don't believe you.
恐怕是真的 除了我没有别的法师
I'm afraid it's true. There's no other Wizard except me.
-你这个骗子 -对
- You humbug. - Yeah.
对 确实如此 我是个骗子
Yes, that's exactly so. I'm a humbug.
你是个很坏的人
You're a very bad man.
不 亲爱的 我是个好人
Oh, no, my dear. I'm a very good man.
但却是个很差的法师
I'm just a very bad wizard.
你答应给锡人的那颗心呢
What about the heart you promised Tin Man?
还有你答应给胆小狮子的勇气呢
And the courage you promised Cowardly Lion?
-稻草人的头脑呢 -稻草人的头脑呢
- And Scarecrow's brain? - And Scarecrow's brain?
每个人都有头脑 这是一种很普通的必备品
Why, anybody can have a brain. That's a very mediocre commodity.
每一个在地球上爬行的小生物...
Every pusillanimous creature that crawls on the earth...
或是在海洋浮游的小生物都有头脑
...or slinks through slimy seas has a brain.
在我的家乡 我们有大学...
Back where I come from, we have universities...
伟大的学府 是人们成为伟大思想家的地方
...seats of great learning, where men go to become great thinkers.
他们的思想深刻 但头脑并不比你更聪明
They think deep thoughts, and with no more brains than you have.
但他们有样你没有的东西 一张文凭
But they have one thing you haven't got. A diploma.
因此 凭借我所拥有的职权...
Therefore, by virtue of the authority vested in me...
来自普卢里巴斯世界大学的授权
Universitatus Committeeatum E Pluribus Unum...
我在此授与你...
...I hereby confer upon you...
-荣誉Th.D博士学位 -Th.D是什么
- ...the honorary degree of Th.D. - Th.D.?
就是思想学博士
That's Doctor of Thinkology.
等腰三角形两边的平方根之和
The sum of the square roots of two sides of an isosceles triangle...
等于剩余边的平方根
...is equal to the square root of the remaining side.
太高兴了 叫人狂喜
Oh, joy. Rapture.
我有头脑了
I've got a brain.
-我该怎么感谢你 -不用谢
- How can I thank you enough? - Well, you can't.
你是思维混乱的受害者
you're a victim of disorganized thinking.
因为你逃避危险而产生的错觉...
You are under the delusion that because you run away from danger...
你不是没有勇气 你是把勇气和智慧混淆了
...you have no courage. You're confusing courage with wisdom.
在我的家乡 我们有种被称为"英雄"的人
Back where I come from, we have men who are called "heroes."
一年一次 他们选出最具坚韧的勇气的人
Once a year, they take their fortitude out of mothballs...
然后在大街上游行
...and parade it down the main street.
他们的勇气不比你更大
And they have no more courage than you have.
但他们有一样你没有的东西 一枚奖章
But they have one thing that you haven't got. A medal.
因此
Therefore...
为了表扬你杰出的表现 非凡的勇气
...for meritorious conduct, extraordinary valor...
勇敢地对抗邪恶的女巫
...conspicuous bravery against wicked witches...
我在此授予你 三重十字勋章
...I award you the Triple Cross.
你现在是勇气军团的成员了
You are now a member of the Legion of Courage.
哎呀 各位 我兴奋的说不出话来了
Shucks, folks, I'm speechless.
至于你 我镀锌的朋友 你想要一颗心
As for you, my galvanized friend, you want a heart.
你不知道你没有心有多幸运
You don't know how lucky you are not to have one.
只有把心变得牢不可破 它才会变得实用
Hearts will never be practical until they can be made unbreakable.
但我还是想要一颗
But I still want one.
在我的家乡 有些人整天只做好事
Back where I come from, there are men who do nothing all day but good deeds.
他们叫做善良...
They are called phil--
做好事的人 他们的心并不比你的大
Good-deed-doers. And their hearts are no bigger than yours.
但他们有一样你没有的东西 一份证明
But they have one thing you haven't got. A testimonial.
因此 考虑到你的善举...
Therefore, in consideration of your kindness...
我很荣幸此时给你...
...I take pleasure at this time in presenting you...
谨向你献上我们的一点敬意和心意
...with a small token of our esteem and affection.
记住 我多愁善感的朋友...
And remember, my sentimental friend...
评判一颗心不是看你的爱有多少
...that a heart is not judged by how much you love...
而是看别人爱你多少
...but by how much you are loved by others.
啊
Ah.
它在跳动
Oh. It ticks.
听 看 它在跳动
Listen. Look, it ticks.
看看我的奖章上写着什么 "勇气"
Read what my medal says. "Courage."
这是真的吗 这是真的吗
Ain't it the truth. Ain't it the truth.
他们都很棒 太好了
Oh, they're all wonderful.
嘿 多萝西呢
Hey, what about Dorothy?
-对啊 多萝西怎么办 -对啊 接下来应该是多萝西
- Yes, how about Dorothy? - Yeah. Dorothy next.
是啊 多萝西...
Yeah, Dorothy...
我想那个黑袋子里没有我要的东西
I don't think there's anything in that black bag for me.
你迫使我做出一个巨变的决定
You force me into a cataclysmic decision.
让多萝西回堪萨斯的唯一办法就是我亲自带她回去
The only way to get Dorothy to Kansas is for me to take her myself.
你愿意吗 你能吗
Oh, will you? Could you? Oh.
聪明的魔法师可以把我变走
But are you clever enough to manage it?
孩子 你真是开门见山 我自己就是堪萨斯人
Child, you cut me to the quick. I'm an old Kansas man myself...
在西部荒野中出生长大
...born and bred in the western wilderness...
我是奇迹仙境公司卓越的首席热气球驾驶员
...premier balloonist par excellence to the Miracle Wonderland Carnival Company.
直到有一天 我在表演平流层飞行技巧...
Until one day, while performing feats of stratospheric skill...
那是人类前所未有的表演
...never before attempted by civilized man...
不幸的现象发生了 气球不能再飞回原处
...an unfortunate phenomena occurred. The balloon failed to return to the fair.
-真的 -你不害怕吗
- It did? - Weren't you frightened?
你在和一个笑着面对死亡的人说话
You are talking to a man who has laughed in the face of death...
对厄运嗤之以鼻 在灾难中轻笑 当时我被吓傻了
...sneered at doom and chuckled at catastrophe. I was petrified.
突然间风向变了...
Suddenly the wind changed...
气球飘进了这座高贵的城市
...and the balloon floated down into this noble city...
在那里我立刻被称赞为仙境里 第一个伟大的魔法师
...where I was instantly acclaimed Oz, the first wizard deluxe.
时间就这样过去 我接受了这份工作
Times being what they were, I accepted the job...
我留着气球 放在能快速逃离的地方
...retaining my balloon against the advent of a quick getaway.
亲爱的多萝茜 有了那气球...
And in that balloon, dear Dorothy...
你和我可以回到普卢里巴斯世界大学
...you and I will return to the land of E Pluribus Unum.
国家博览会
奥马哈
我的朋友们 我是说 我的朋友们
My friends. I mean, my friends!
这绝对是有史以来最好的展示...
This is positively the finest exhibition ever to be shown...
起码前无古人
be that as it may.
我 你们的魔法师 伯拉图阿塔...
I, your Wizard per ardua ad alta...
我即将踏上一场危险的...
...am about to embark upon a hazardous...
技术上无法解释的旅程...
...and technically unexplainable journey...
进入外层平流层
...into the outer stratosphere.
为了维持与...
To confer, converse...
我魔法师兄弟间的亲密关系
...and otherwise hobnob with my brother wizards.
我特此命令 直到...
And I hereby decree that until what time...
在我不知何时会回来之前...
...if any, that I return...
稻草人 凭借他高超的头脑
...the Scarecrow, by virtue of his highly superior brains...
将代替我统治这里...
...shall rule in my stead...
由锡人协助 因为他有宏伟的心胸...
...assisted by the Tin Man, by virtue of his magnificent heart...
还有狮子 因为他有坚毅的勇气
...and the Lion, by virtue of his courage.
你们要像服从我一样服从他们 谢谢
Obey them as you would me. Thank you.
托托 回来 托托
Oh, Toto. Come back. Toto.
别丢下我就走了 我马上就回来
Don't go without me. I'll be right back.
拦住那只狗
Stop that dog.
这是个极度不寻常的突发状况
This is a highly irregular procedure.
-完全无法预测 -气球在上升
- This is absolutely unprecedented. - The balloon's going up.
-破坏我的离开 -回来 回来
- Ruined my exit. - Come back! Come back!
别丢下我就走了 求你回来
Don't go without me. Please come back!
我不能回来了 我不懂得如何操作
I can't come back. I don't know how it works.
再见 各位
Goodbye, folks.
再见
Goodbye!
槽了 我永远回不了家了
Oh, now I'll never get home.
那就跟我们在一起 多萝西
Stay with us then, Dorothy.
我们都很爱你
We all love you.
我们不想让你走
We don't want you to go.
你们真是太好了...
That's very kind of you...
但这里永远不会像堪萨斯
...but this could never be like Kansas.
艾姆婶婶一定不知道我现在出了什么事
Auntie Em must have stopped wondering what happened to me by now.
稻草人 我该怎么办
Oh, Scarecrow, what am I going to do?
你看
Look.
能帮你的人来了
Here's someone who can help you.
-你愿意帮我吗 你能帮我吗 -你已经不再需要帮助了
- Will you help me? Can you help me? - You don't need help any longer.
你一直都有能力回到堪萨斯
You've always had the power to go back to Kansas.
-我有吗 -那你为什么不早告诉她
- I have? - Then why didn't you tell her before?
因为她不会相信我 她必须自己去学会
Because she wouldn't have believed me. She had to learn it for herself.
你学到了什么 多萝西
What have you learned, Dorothy?
嗯...
Well...
我想它...
I think that it--
仅仅想见亨利叔叔和艾姆婶婶是不够的
That it wasn't enough just to want to see Uncle Henry and Auntie Em.
如果我再去寻找我内心的渴望...
And it's that if I ever go looking for my heart's desire again...
我只想回到我家后院 不想更远...
...I won't look any further than my own back yard...
因为如果不在那里...
...because if it isn't there...
我就失去了人生的开始
...I never really lost it to begin with.
对吗
Is that right?
就是那些
That's all it is.
但这很简单 我早该想到的
But that's so easy. I should've thought of it for you.
-我早该在心里感受到 -她得自己找出来才行
- I should've felt it in my heart. - She had to find it out for herself.
这双神奇的仙鞋能在两秒钟内把你带回家
Now those magic slippers will take you home in two seconds.
-托托也能吗 -托托也能
- Toto too? - Toto too.
-现在吗 -随时都可以
- Now? - Whenever you wish.
亲爱的 那太好了 简直令人难以置信
Oh, dear. That's too wonderful to be true.
真是...
Oh, it's...
我真是不知道该怎么说再见
It's gonna be so hard to say goodbye.
我也爱你们
I love you all too.
再见 锡人
Goodbye, Tin Man.
别哭
Oh, don't cry.
你会锈得很厉害的
You'll rust so dreadfully.
在这里 这是你的油壶
Here. Here's your oilcan.
-再见 -现在我知道我有一颗心...
- Goodbye. - Now I know I've got a heart...
因为它已经碎了
...because it's breaking.
再见 狮子 我知道这样不对...
Goodbye, Lion. I know it isn't right...
但我会想念你在找到勇气之前...
...but I'm gonna miss the way you used to holler for help...
哭喊着大声呼救的样子
...before you found your courage.
如果没有你 我永远也找不到勇气
I would never have found it if it hadn't been for you.
我想我会最想你的
I think I'll miss you most of all.
-你准备好了吗 -好了
- Are you ready now? - Yes.
说再见 托托
Say goodbye, Toto.
-好了 我准备好了 -闭上你的眼睛
- Yes, I'm ready now. - Then close your eyes...
两脚并拢 鞋跟互相碰三下
...and tap your heels together three times...
然后对自己说
...and think to yourself:
家最温暖
"There's no place like home.
"家最温暖"
" There's no place like home."
家最温暖
There's no place like home.
-醒醒 甜心 -家最温暖
- Wake up, honey. - There's no place like home.
家最温暖
There's no place like home.
家最...
There's no place....
多萝西 亲爱的 是艾姆婶婶 亲爱的
Dorothy, dear. It's Aunt Em, darling.
艾姆婶婶 是你
Oh, Auntie Em, it's you.
-是我 亲爱的 -你好 有人在家吗
- Yes, darling. - Hello there. Anybody home?
我顺道经过 因为我听说小女孩...
I dropped by because I heard the little girl got caught in the big--
-她现在看起来没事了 -她头上撞得很厉害
- Well, she seems all right now. - She got quite a bump on the head.
我们还以为她要离开我们呢
We kind of thought she was gonna leave us.
但我确实离开了你们 问题就在这里
But I did leave you. That's just the trouble.
我一直想回来
And I tried to get back for days.
好了 好了 安静地躺着吧
There, there, lie quiet now.
-你只是做了个恶梦 -肯定是
- You just had a bad dream. - Sure.
记得我吗
Remember me...
你的老朋友 汉克
...your old pal, Hunk?
还有我 希格利
And me, Hickory?
你不会忘记我的脸 对吧
You couldn't forget my face, could you?
不 但这不是梦 这是个地方
No. But it wasn't a dream. It was a place.
你和你和你
And you and you and you...
还有你也在场
...and you were there.
当然了
Sure.
但你们不可能去 对不对
But you couldn't have been, could you?
当我们做梦的时候 会梦到很多傻事
We dream lots of silly things when we--
不是 艾姆婶婶 这是个真实的地方
No, Aunt Em, this was a real, truly live place.
我记得有些地方不太好...
And I remember that some of it wasn't very nice...
但大部分都很美
...but most of it was beautiful.
但不管怎样 我一直对大家说"我想回家"
But just the same, all I kept saying to everybody was, "I want to go home."
他们就送我回家了
And they sent me home.
难道没有人相信我吗
Doesn't anybody believe me?
我们当然相信你 多萝西
Of course we believe you, Dorothy.
不管怎样 托托 我们回家了
But anyway, Toto, we're home.
家 这是我的房间...
Home. And this is my room...
你们都在这里
...and you're all here.
我再也不会离开这里了...
And I'm not going to leave here ever, ever again...
因为我爱你们所有的人
...because I love you all.
艾姆婶婶...
And oh, Auntie Em...
...家最温暖
...there's no place like home.
剧终
谢谢观赏